I'm going to tell you about why I became a sculptor,
سوف أخبركم لماذا اصبحت نحاتاً,
and you may think that sculptors,
و من الممكن أن تظنوا ان النحاتين,
well, they deal with meta, they deal with objects,
حسناً, يتعاملون مع الفوقية ، و يتعاملون مع الأشياء،
they deal with bodies,
و مع الاجسام,
but I think, really, what I care about most
و لكني أعتقد ان ما يهمني اكثر
is making space, and that's what I've called this talk:
هو صناعة مكان و هو ما سميت به هذا حديث:
Making Space.
صناعة مكان.
Space that exists within us,
مكان موجود بداخلنا,
and without us.
و بدوننا.
So, when I was a child,
لذلك عندما كنت طفلاً
I don't know how many of you grew up in the '50s,
أنا لا ادري كم منكم نشأ في الخمسينات,
but I was sent upstairs for an enforced rest. (Laughter)
و لكني كنت أرسل الي الاعلي لقيلولة اجبارية.(ضحك)
It's a really bad idea. I mean, after lunch, you're, you know,
انها في الحقيقة فكرة سيئة. أعني, بعد الغداء, أنت, أنتم تعلمون,
you're six, and you want to go and climb a tree.
في عمر السادسة و تريد ان تتسلق شجرة.
But I had to go upstairs, this tiny little room
و لكنك مضطر للصعود للاعلي, هذة الغرفة الصغيرة
that was actually made out of an old balcony,
التي كانت في الحقيقة بلكونة قديمة,
so it was incredibly hot, small and light,
لذلك كانت غرفة حارة جداً صغيرة و خفيفة
and I had to lie there. It was ridiculous.
و كان علي أن أستلقي هناك. كانت سخيفة
But anyway, for some reason, I promised myself
و لكن عموما, لسبب ما , وعدت نفسي
that I wasn't going to move,
انني لن اتحرك,
that I was going to do this thing that Mummy
و انني سافعل الشئ الذي طلبت مني أمي
wanted me to do.
أن اقوم به.
And there I was, lying there in this tiny space,
وهناك كنت, استلقي في مساحة صغيرة جداً
hot, dark, claustrophobic, matchbox-sized, behind my eyes,
حار, مظلم, خانقة, في حجم علبة الكبريت, خلف نظري
but it was really weird, like, after this went on
و لكن كان حقاً غريباً وبعد ان استمر الامر
for days, weeks, months, that space would get bigger
لايام و اسابيع و اشهر, المساحة اصبحت اكبر
and darker and cooler
و اكثر ظلامة و برودة
until I really looked forward to that half an hour
حتي اصبحت اتطلع للنصف ساعة
of enforced immobility and rest,
من الخمود والراحة القسرية،
and I really looked forward to going to that place
و كنت اتطلع للذهاب لذلك المكان
of darkness.
المظلم.
Do you mind if we do something completely different?
هل تمانع لو قمنا بعمل شيء مختلف تماما؟
Can we all just close our eyes for a minute?
هل يمكن ان نغلق جميعا اعيننا لدقيقة؟
Now, this isn't going to be freaky.
الان, لن يكون الامر مريب
It isn't some cultic thing. (Laughter)
انه ليست نوع من الطقوس.(ضحك)
It's just, it's just, I just would like us all to go there.
انها فقط , انها فقط, انا فقط اريد ان نذهب كلنا هناك.
So I'm going to do it too. We'll all be there together.
و لذلك ساقوم بفعل ذلك ايضاً. سوف نكون معا هناك.
So close your eyes for a minute.
لذلك اغلقوا اعينكم لدقيقة.
Here we are, in a space,
نحن هنا, في الفضاء,
the subjective, collective space of the darkness of the body.
الفضاء، ذاتية وجماعية من ظلام الجسم.
I think of this as the place of imagination,
افكر بهذا كمكان للخيال،
of potential,
من إمكانات،
but what are its qualities?
ولكن ما هي صفاته؟
It is objectless. There are no things in it.
لا توجد أشياء في ذلك.
It is dimensionless. It is limitless.
من دون أبعاد. لا حدود لها.
It is endless.
لا نهاية لها.
Okay, open your eyes.
حسنا، افتح عينيك.
That's the space that I think sculpture --
هذا هو الفضاء أعتقد أن النحت-
which is a bit of a paradox, sculpture that is about
وهو قليلاً من مفارقة، والنحت الذي هو
making material propositions --
عبارة عن تقديم مقترحات مادية-
but I think that's the space
ولكن أعتقد أن هذا الفضاء
that sculpture can connect us with.
أن النحت يمكن ان يجعلنا نتصل به.
So, imagine we're in the middle of America.
لذا، تخيل أننا في وسط أمريكا.
You're asleep. You wake up,
انت نائماً. و تستيقظ،
and without lifting your head from the earth
ودون رفع راسك من على الأرض
on your sleeping bag, you can see for 70 miles.
في كيس النوم الخاص بك، يمكنك أن ترى على بعد 70 ميلا.
This is a dry lake bed.
وهذا سرير في بحيرة جافة.
I was young. I'd just finished art school.
كنت صغيراً. وقد انتهيت للتو مدرسة للفنون.
I wanted to do something that was working
أردت أن اقوم بشيئ كان يعمل
directly with the world, directly with place.
مباشرة مع العالم، مباشرة مع المكان.
This was a wonderful place, because it was a place
وهذا مكان رائع، لأنه كان مكاناً
where you could imagine that you were the
حيث يمكن أن تتصور أن تكون
first person to be there.
أول شخص يكون هناك.
It was a place where nothing very much had happened.
كان مكاناً حيث لم يحدث فيه شيئ.
Anyway, bear with me.
على أي حال، تحمل معي.
I picked up a hand-sized stone,
التقطت حجاراً بحجم اليد
threw it as far as I was able,
ألقيت بها ابعد ما يمكنني،
it was about 22 meters.
كان حوالي 22 مترا.
I then cleared all the stones within that radius
ثم قمت بأخذ جميع الأحجار في نصف القطر ذلك
and made a pile.
و قمت بعمل كومة.
And that was the pile, by the way.
و تلك هي الكومة، بالمناسبة
And then, I stood on the pile,
وبعد ذلك، وقفت على الكومة،
and threw all of those rocks out again,
وألقيت كل من تلك الصخور بها مرة أخرى،
and here is rearranged desert.
وهنا صحراء اعيد ترتيبها.
You could say, well, it doesn't look very different
حسنا، يمكن القول أنها لا تبدو مختلفة جداً
from when he started.
من الاول
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
What's all the fuss about?
لما كل هذا العناء؟
In fact, Chris was worried and said,
في الواقع، كان كريس قلق وقال:
"Look, don't show them that slide,
"انظر، لا تبين لهم تلك الشريحة،
because they're just going to think you're another one of
لأنهم سيعتقدون أنك واحد اَخر من
those crazy modern artists who doesn't do much.
هؤلاء الفنانين المعاصرين المجانين الذين لا يقومون بالكثير.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But the fact is, this is evidence
ولكن بالحقيقة أن هذا دليل
of a living body on other bodies,
لجسم حي على اجسام اخرى
rocks that have been the subject of geological formation,
الصخور التي كانت موضوع التشكلات الجيولوجية،
erosion, the action of time on objects.
تآكل، تأثير الوقت على الاشياء.
This is a place, in a way, that I just
وهذا مكان، بطريقة، أنا فقط
would like you to, in a way, look at differently
أود أن تنظروا اليه بطريقة مختلفة
because of this event that has happened in it,
بسبب هذا الحدث الذي حدث فيه
a human event,
حدث بشري،
and in general, it just asks us to look again
وعموما، فإنه فقط يطلب منا أن ننظر مرة أخرى
at this world, so different from, in a way,
في هذا العالم، مختلف كثيرا عنه، في طريقة،
the world that we have been sharing with each other,
العالم الذي نتقاسمه مع بعضها البعض،
the technological world,
العالم التكنولوجي،
to look again at the elemental world.
لننظر مرة أخرى في العالم العنصري.
The elemental world that we all live in is that space
العالم العنصري الذي نعيش فيه هو أن الفضاء
that we all visited together, the darkness of the body.
الذي زرناه جميعاً معاً. ظلمة الجسم
I wanted to start again with that environment,
أريد أن ابدأ مرة أخرى مع تلك البيئة،
the environment of the intimate, subjective space
بيئة الفضاء الحميمة والذاتية
that each of us lives in, but from the other side
التي كل واحد منا يعيش فيها، ولكن من الجانب الآخر
of appearance.
من المظهر.
So here is a daily activity of the studio.
هنا أحد الأنشطة اليومية للاستوديو.
You can see I don't do much. I'm just standing there,
يمكنك أن ترى أنا لا افعل الكثير. وأنا فقط واقف هناك،
again with my eyes closed, and other people
مرة أخرى مع عيناي مغلقة، وأشخاص آخرين
are molding me, evidential.
يصبون فيني،
This is an indexical register of a lived moment
هذا هو مسجل دليلي للحظة المعاشة
of a body in time.
للجسد في الوقت
Can we map that space, using the language of neutrinos
هل يمكننا تخطيط هذا الفضاء، استخدام لغة النيوترونات
or cosmic rays, taking the bounding condition of the body
أو الأشعة الكونية، بأخذ الظروف الملزمة للجسم
as its limit, but in complete reversal of, in a way,
كحد له، لكن ف بالعكس تماماً، بطريقة،
the most traditional Greek idea of pointing?
الفكرة اليونانية الأكثر تقليدية للإشارة؟
In the old days they used to take a lump of Pentelic marble
في الأيام الخوالي اعتادوا ان يأخذوا كتلة من الرخام البنتالي
and drill from the surface in order to identify the skin,
و يحفرون على السطح من اجل ان يتعرفوا على القشرة
the appearance,
المظهر،
what Aristotle defined as the distinction
ما عرفه أرسطو كالتمييز
between substance and appearance,
بين الجوهر والمظهر،
the thing that makes things visible,
الاشياء التي تجعل الأشياء مرئية،
but here we're working from the other side.
ولكن نحن نعمل هنا من الجانب الآخر.
Or can we do it as an exclusive membrane?
أو هل يمكننا أن نفعل ذلك كغشاء حصري؟
This is a lead case made around the space
هذا صندوق رصاص صنع حول الفضاء
that my body occupied, but it's now void.
الذي يحتله جسدي، ولكنها الان فارغة.
This is a work called "Learning To See."
هذا عمل يسمى "تعلم ان تنظر."
It's a bit of, well, we could call it night,
أنها قليلاً من، حسناً يمكن أن نسميها ليل،
we could call it the 96 percent of gravity
يمكن أن نسميه 96% من الجاذبية
that we don't know about, dark matter,
التي لا نعرف عنها، المادة المظلمة،
placed in space, anyway, another version of a human space
وضعت في الفضاء، على أي حال، شكل اخر من فضاء الانسان
in space at large, but I don't know if you can see,
في مساحة كبيرة، ولكن لا أعرف إذا كان يمكنك أن ترى،
the eyes are indicated, they're closed.
العيون محددة، و مغلقة.
It's called "Learning To See" because it's about an object
انها تسمى "تعلم ان ترى" لأنها حول كائن
that hopefully works reflexively and talks about that
التي نأمل أن يعمل بالغريزة ويتحدث عن
vision or connection with the darkness of the body
الرؤية أو اتصال مع ظلام الجسم
that I see as a space of potential.
التي أراها كمساحة من إمكانيات.
Can we do it another way, using the language
يمكننا أن نفعل ذلك بطريقة أخرى، باستخدام اللغة
of particles around a nucleus, and talk about the body
من الجسيمات حول النواة، والحديث عن الجسم
as an energy center?
كمركز للطاقة؟
No longer about statues, no longer having to take that
لم يعد حول التماثيل، لم تعد بالحاجة إلى أن تأخذ
duty of standing, the standing of a human body,
واجب الوقوف، وقوف جسم الإنسان،
or the standing of a statue, release it,
أو وقوف تمثال، اتركه،
allow it to be an energy field, a space in space
اتح له أن يكون في حقل طاقة، مكان في الفضاء
that talks about human life, between becoming an entropy
ذلك الحديث عن الحياة البشرية، وبين أن تصبح الكون
as a sort of concentration of attention,
كنوع من تركيز الاهتمام،
a human place of possibility in space at large.
مكان بشري من الإمكانية في الفضاء ككل.
Is there another way?
هل هناك طريقة أخرى؟
Dark matter now placed against a horizon.
وضعت المادة المظلمة الآن ضد أفق.
If minds live in bodies, if bodies live in clothes,
إذا العقول تعيش في الهيئات، إذا كانت الهيئات تعيش في الملابس،
and then in rooms, and then in buildings,
ومن ثم في الغرف، ومن ثم في المباني،
and then in cities, do they also have a final skin,
وثم في المدن، كما لديهم جلد اخير،
and is that skin perceptual?
وهو الإدراك الحسي للجلد؟
The horizon.
الأفق.
And is art about
والفن حول
trying to imagine what lies beyond the horizon?
في محاولة تصور ما يكمن وراء الأفق؟
Can we use, in a way, a body as an empty catalyst
هل يمكن أن نستخدم، بطريقة ما، جسم كعامل مسرع فارغ
for a kind of empathy with the experience
لنوع من التعاطف مع الخبرة
of space-time as it is lived, as I am standing here
الزمان مع المكان كما هو عاش، كما أقف هنا
in front of you trying to feel and make a connection
أمامك احاول أن اشعر و اتصل
in this space-time that we are sharing,
في هذا الزمان و المكان نحن نتقاسم،
can we use, at it were, the memory of a body,
هل يمكننا استخدام، في أنها كانت، ذاكرة الجسم،
of a human space in space to catalyze
لفضاء الإنسان في الفضاء لتحفيز
an experience, again, firsthand experience,
تجربة، مرة أخرى، تجربة مباشرة،
of elemental time.
للمرة الأولى.
Human time, industrial time, tested against
زمن البشر، زمن الصناعة، ضد
the time of the tides, in which these memories
زمن الامواج، في هذه الذكريات
of a particular body, that could be any body,
لجسم معين يمكن أن يكون أي الجسم،
multiplied as in the time of mechanical reproduction,
مضروب كما هو الحال في وقت الاستنساخ الميكانيكي،
many times, placed over three square miles,
مرات عديدة، ووضع في ثلاثة أميال مربعة،
a mile out to sea,
ميل خارجاً إلى البحر،
disappearing, in different conditions of day and night.
تختفي، في ظروف مختلفة من النهار والليل.
You can see this work. It's on the mouth of the Mersey,
يمكنك أن ترى هذا العمل. في شاطئ ميرسي،
just outside Liverpool.
فقط خارج ليفربول.
And there you can see what a Liverpool sea looks like
وهناك يمكنك أن ترى بحر ليفربول
on a typical afternoon.
في فترة ما بعد الظهيرة.
The pieces appear and disappear,
القطع تظهر وتختفي،
but maybe more importantly --
لكن ربما الأهم من ذلك-
this is just looking north from the center of the installation --
وهذا هو فقط يواجه الشمال من مركز التثبيت-
they create a field, a field that involves
لقد أنشأوا حقل، حقل الذي يتعلق ب
living and the surrogate bodies in a kind of relation,
الاجسام الحية و البديلة في نوع من العلاقة،
a relation with each other and a relation with that limit,
علاقة مع بعضها البعض وعلاقة مع ذلك الحد،
the edge, the horizon.
على حافة الأفق.
Just moving on, is it possible,
هل من الممكن،
taking that idea of mind, body, body-building,
أخذ هذه الفكرة من العقل والجسم، بناء الجسم،
to supplant the first body,
لتحل محل الهيئة الأولى،
the biological body, with the second,
الجسم البيولوجي مع الثاني،
the body of architecture and the built environment.
الجسم للهندسة المعمارية والبيئة العمرانية.
This is a work called "Room for the Great Australian Desert."
هذا عمل يسمى "غرفة للصحراء الأسترالية الكبرى".
It's in an undefined location
في مكان غير معرف
and I've never published where it is.
ولم انشر ابدأ أين هي.
It's an object for the mind.
انها كائن للعقل.
I think of it as a 21st-century Buddha.
أعتقد أنه بوذا القرن الحادي والعشرين.
Again, the darkness of the body,
مرة أخرى، ظلام الجسم،
now held within this bunker shape
و الان موجود على شكل المستودع هذا
of the minimum position that a body needs to occupy,
في الوضعية التي تحتاج اقل مساحة
a crouching body.
هيئة القرفصة.
There's a hole at the anus, penis level.
هناك ثقب في فتحه الشرج، مستوى القضيب.
There are holes at ears. There are no holes at the eyes.
وهناك ثقوب في الأذنين. ولا توجد ثقوب للعيون.
There's a slot for the mouth. It's two and a half inches thick,
وهناك فتحه للفم. ذات سمك اثنين ونصف بوصة،
concrete with a void interior.
الخرسانة مع فراغ داخلي.
Again, a site found with a completely flat
مرة أخرى، موقع وجد مع
360-degree horizon.
360 درجة الأفق مسطح تماماً.
This is just simply asking, again,
وهذا هو ببساطة مجرد السؤال، مرة أخرى،
as if we had arrived for the first time,
كما لو أننا قد وصلنا لأول مرة،
what is the relationship of the human project
ما هي علاقة المشروع البشري
to time and space?
للزمان والمكان؟
Taking that idiom of, as it were,
بأخذ هذه العبارة الاصطلاحية، كما لو كان،
the darkness of the body transferred to architecture,
ظلام الجسم نقل إلى الهندسة المعمارية،
can you use architectural space not for living
هل يمكنك استخدام الفضاء المعماري ليس للمعيشة
but as a metaphor,
ولكن كاستعارة،
and use its systolic, diastolic
واستخدم فضاءه الانقباضي، الانبساطي
smaller and larger spaces to provide a kind of
الأصغر والأكبر لتوفير نوع من
firsthand somatic narrative for a journey through space,
السرد الجسدية المباشر لرحلة عبر الفضاء،
light and darkness?
النور والظلام؟
This is a work of some proportion and some weight
هذا عمل بعضه نسبة وبعض الوزن
that makes the body into a city, an aggregation of cells
الذي يحول الجسم إلى مدينة، تجميعاً للخلايا
that are all interconnected
التي هي مترابطة جميعا
and that allow certain visual access
و التي تسمح ببعض الوصول البصري
at certain places.
في أماكن معينة.
The last work that I just wanted to share with you
العمل الأخير الذي أردت ان اشاركه معكم
is "Blind Light," which is perhaps
هو "الضوء الأعمى،" الذي ربما يكون
the most open work,
العمل الأكثر انفتاحاً،
and in a conference of radical openness,
وفي اتحاد لانفتاح جذري،
I think maybe this is as radical as I get,
وأعتقد ربما هذا هو اكثر جذرية استطيع الوصول اليها
using light and water vapor as my materials.
استخدام الضوء وبخار الماء كمواد
Here is a box
هنا صندوق
filled at one and a half atmospheres of atmospheric pressure,
بضغط يساوي واحد و نصف من الضغط الجوي
with a cloud and with very bright light.
مع سحابة و ضوء ساطع جداً.
As you walk towards the ever-open threshold,
كما يمكنك السير نحو البداية الغير منتهية
you disappear, both to yourselves and to others.
أنت تختفي، لنفسك وإلى الآخرين.
If you hold your hand out in front of you,
إذا رفعت بيدك امامك
you can't see it.
لا يمكنك رؤيتها.
If you look down, you can't see your feet.
إذا نظرت إلى أسفل، لا يمكنك رؤية قدميك.
You are now consciousness without an object,
أنت الآن في حالة ادراك بدون اي شيئ،
freed from the dimensionful
متحرر من الابعادية
and measured way in which life links us
و الطريقة المقاسة التي تربط الحياة بنا
to the obligatory.
إلى الإلزامية.
But this is a space that is actually filled with people,
ولكن هذا الفضاء في الواقع مليء بالناس،
disembodied voices,
أصوات بلا جسد،
and out of that ambient environment,
وخارج تلك البيئة المحيطة،
when people come close to your own body zone,
عندما يقترب الناس من جسمك
very close, they appear to you as representations.
بشدة. أنهم يبدون لك كتصورات.
When they appear close to the edge,
عندما يظهروا قريباً من الحافة،
they are representations, representations in which
كتصورات، تصورات حيث
the viewers have become the viewed.
أصبح المشاهدين ما يشاهد.
For me, art is not about objects of high monetary exchange.
الفن بالنسبة لي، ليس حول اشياء ذات تبادلات نقدية عالية.
It's about reasserting our firsthand experience
أنها عن إعادة تأكيد خبرتنا المباشرة
in present time.
في الوقت الحاضر.
As John Cage said,
كما قال جون كيج،
"We are not moving towards some kind of goal.
"نحن لا نتحرك نحو نوع من الهدف.
We are at the goal, and it is changing with us.
نحن في الهدف، وهو يتغير معنا.
If art has any purpose, it is to open our eyes to that fact."
لو للفن هدف, فهو لتفتح عينيك علي هذة الحقيقة."
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)